Mss.B.M58.1
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Report of committee on the Michaux legacy on Rothrock's proposed lectures and Heilprin's paper on Mexican forestry, Nov. 5, 1891; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: J[ohn] Sergeant Price. 2p. and end.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Philadelphia, Nov. 18, 1891; 10-1/2x8; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown, Typed L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning the best usage of the income from the Michaux legacy.
  - List of Michaux forestry lectures, 1891-1892; 10x7-3/4; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Jan. 19, 1892; 8x5; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.N. in 3d person 1p., end. Cannot accept appointment to the Michaux committee.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 20, 1892; 8x5; Fraley, F., (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Places I. C. Martindale on Michaux committee.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 31, 1892; 6x4; Hallowell, Sarah Catherine Fraley
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 3p. Father, F. Fraley, approves Heilprin for Michaux committee. Father's health much improved.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 3, 1892; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Philadelphia, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Concerns Heilprin's paper on "Temperate and Alpine Floras of the Giant Volcanoes of Mexico," a report of the Michaux Legacy Committee. For paper, see: A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. 30, pages 4-15.
  - Report of committee on Michaux legacy on grant for Rothrock's forestry lectures to be held at the academy of natural sciences, Sept. 16, 1892; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: J[ohn] Sergeant Price. 2p. and end. ----Copy.
  - Report of committee on Michaux legacy on Rothrock's request for grant for work on Pennsylvania forests, Dec. 29, 1892; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 29, 1893; 7x5-1/4; Fraley, F., (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Philadelphia], L. 3p. Appoints H. F. Jayne to vacancy on Michaux committee. Discusses finances of Phillips prize essay fund. Refers to J. S. Price.
  - Resolution pertaining to the forests of Pennsylvania, Feb. 17, 1893; 9-3/4x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p. and end. [In hand of Rothrock?]
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Philadelphia, Dec. 5, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, Typed D.S. 1p., end. Asks grant for course for Michaux forestry lectures to be held at the University.
  - Report of committee on Michaux legacy on Rothrock's request for grant for forestry lectures to be held at the University, Dec. 14, 1893; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: J[ohn] Sergeant Price. 1p and end. ----Copy.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Jan. 6, 1894; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Withdraws proposed schedule of Michaux forestry lectures.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 20, 1894; 6x4; Fraley, F., (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Philadelphia], L. 4p. Concerns Michaux committee. Appoints Mitchell, Ryder, Bache to committee on Dr. Wright's paper. Refers to Price, Billings, Cramp.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., June 15, 1895; 11x8-1/2; McClung, C. M.
    Knoxville, Tennessee, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of Michaux's journal.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., June 21, 1895; 11x8-1/2; McClung, C. M.
    Knoxville, Tennessee, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends payment for copy of Michaux's journal.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Dec. 20, 1895; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Cambridge botanical supply co.
    Cambridge, Massachusetts, L. on postal card 1p., end. and add. Orders copy of Michaux journal.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, March 25, 1896; 9-1/2x6; University of Vermont
    Burlington, Vermont, A.L.S.: Thomas R. Barnum, Librarian 1p., end. Asks about copies of journals of Michaux and Pursh.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 6, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Brown, Arthur Erwin, b. 1850
    [Philadelphia], A.L.S. 2p. Cannot serve on Michaux Legacy committee.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 9, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F., (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Philadelphia], L.S. 1p. Appoints B. Landreth to Michaux Legacy Committee.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Oct. 22, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown, [Pennsylvania], A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Michaux legacy committee. Refers to A. Heilprin.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Oct. 28, 1897; 9x5-3/4; American Philosophical Society Committee on Michaux legacy
    A.L.S.: Thomas Meehan. 1p. and end. Concerning expenditure of the Michaux legacy income.
  - Letter to [Isaac] Minis Hays, Feb. 19, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    [Philadelphia], A.L.S. 1p., end. Michaux Committee to consider appropriation.
  - Report of committee on Michaux legacy for purchase of books on forestry, Feb. 24, 1898; 12-1/2x7-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Thomas Meehan, Burnet Landreth, and Henry Trimble. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 19, 1911; 8-1/2x5-1/2 and 9x5-3/4; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    A.L.S. 1p. and enc. of 9p. Concerning correspondence between J. Vaughan and F. A. Michaux in the APS.
  - Letter to Cardot, January 27; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Forwards volumes from Philadelphia to the Institut de France.
  - Note to Bertrand, July 3; 8x5; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.N.S. 1p. and add. In French. Has placed publications in chest.
  - Letter to [François André] Michaux, Oct. 4; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Grégoire, Henri, 1750-1831
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. and end. In French. Friendly letter. Refers to Griffith.
  - Bill of lading to J[o]hn Vaughan for the A.P.S., undated; 7-1/4x9-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    1p. In French.
  - Catalogue des ouvrages periodiques envoÿe par la Société philosophique..., undated; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    D. 2p., end.
  - Concerning the APS Michaux Legacy, undated
  - List of books for John Vaughan for the A.P.S., undated; 17x11; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    C. W. Peale. Muhlenberg, etc D. 2p. Lists books by Palisot de Beauvois. Sends books to C. Wistar, also.
  - List of books desired by the A.P.S. to [François André Michaux?], undated; 8x6-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 1p.
  - List of publications shipped to John Vaughan for the A.P.S., undated; 9-1/2x7; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    FILM 199 FRAME 702
    C. Wistar, W. Barton, Thomas Jefferson, etc. A.D. 2p. In French.
  - Memorandum pertaining to the legacy left to the APS by F. A. Michaux, undated
    Scope and Contents note.
  - Memorandum of publications received from Michaux for various persons, undated; 10x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 2 leaves. Refers to C. Wistar.
  - Projet concernant l'etablissement d'une pépinière d'arbres et plantes étrangeres dans les environs de Bayonne, undated; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Photostat of A(?).D. 5p. and end. From original in the library of the Museum of Natural History, Paris. ----Film 298. On same film is A. Michaux's Arbres de l'Amérique septentrionale.
  - Report of committee on the oaks in Fairmount Park purchased by the Michaux legacy, undated; 6-1/4x8; American Philosophical Society